Android 1.0 launched in 2008. And in just the six year since then,
there has been 11 new major platform releases. On the Android developer side,
we show the relative number of active Android devices running a given platform
version in this pie chart, because pie charts are awesome. For our purposes
though, you're really better off looking at this as a histogram. If you squint,
you can almost see a vaguely bell-shaped curve, with the oldest releases here at
the left, their popularity dropping off as devices are upgraded or
replaced. The largest proportion of devices are here in the middle,
representing devices about two years old. And the newest platforms,
gaining popularity as new phones are released or upgrades go out,
are here on the right. So with that in mind, the Min SDK acts as your low-pass
filter. Google Play won't show your app on devices running a platform version
lower than its minimum SDK version. So why not just set the Min SDK to one and
support everyone? Generally, you'll want to target as many users as you can, but
there's a cost associated with supporting some of these older versions.
Things like creating different execution paths around deprecated or
update APIs or presenting a different UX to devices with different features. So
you need to balance the opportunity of expanding your audience with the cost of
supporting those new users. Also, remember that each release introduced with it
new APIs and hardware support. So it may not make sense to
make your app available to devices that don't support your minimum feature set.
By comparison, the Target SDK is not a high-pass filter.
It's used only to declare which platform version you've tested on.
An app targeted to a certain API will continue to be forward compatible on
future releases. The platform uses the Target SDK values in case a future
platform makes a significant change to expected behavior. This ensures your app
doesn't break when a user's phone gets upgraded. If you're developing a new app,
there's really no reason to target anything but the latest Android version. And
once your app has been released, make it a point to update your Target SDK and
test as soon as possible when new platform releases roll out so you can take
advantage of every new platform optimization and improvement it has to offer.